We think Einstein was probably
a good kisser.
He's rumoured to have said,
'Everything should be made as simple as possible,
but not simpler.'
Whether it was him
or some other genius
with a brain the size of a planet,
it's still good advice.
So make short,
simple words your first choice.
They're the most powerful.
Just look in any dictionary.
Short words have the longest entries.
It's easy to think that
long words make you sound
smarter or more important.
But why use your brain to translate
a short word into a long one?
Your readers will only have
to use their brains
to translate it back again.
Your good ideas will shine through
in clear,
straightforward language.
No one's saying you have to use short words
all the time.
That would be boring.
Remember that quote:
'Everything should be made as simple
as possible,
but NOT simpler.'
Sometimes,
you might need to use longer
words or technical jargon
words if they're
right for your reader.
But when you do,
think of each jargon word
as a stepping stone
that moves the reader
towards your meaning.
You want to make the spaces
in between the stepping stones as
easy to cross as possible.
So, look at
the words in between and make
sure they're as short
and simple as they can be.
You don't have to be Einstein
to have big ideas,
or to do a great job.
But think of him when you're
writing at work, and then KISS.